Mark Rosenkrans

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

404.519.9353 | mark.rosenkrans@gmail.com | markrosenkrans.net | linkedin.com/in/mrosenkrans

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with extensive experience working as a Scrum Master on Agile software development projects. My background has empowered me with the ability to work with people both on and offshore. Proven track record of delivering sprints and projects that delight customers.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Certified Scrum Master, Project Management, Agile methodology, leadership, Kanban boards, business analysis, requirements gathering, software development life cycle, iTrack/JIRA, Six Sigma Green Belt, Certified Nurse Aide

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly - Atlanta, GA 3-month full-time course

Bachelor of Business Administration, Computer Information Systems

GA State University - Robinson College of Business - Atlanta, GA President of Association for Information Systems

Associate of Applied Science, Computer Networking

Delgado College - New Orleans, LA President of Mu Alpha Theta, President of CyberNET, Senator SGA Honor Society: Phi Theta Kappa

Certified Nurse Aide

Covenant CNA School - Atlanta, GA License: CN0030042962 (Feb 2016-Feb 2022) First Aid/CPR/AED (Renewed Jan 2020-Jan 2022)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Freelance Atlanta, GA 2019-2020 Graduated from General Assembly and currently doing freelance work for Atlanta non-profit organizations:

Seed & Feed Marching Abominable, Compassion House, Echo Healing PROJECTS:

- Not Hangman: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Band App: MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, Node.js
- Budget App: MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, Material-UI
- Library System: React, Python, Django, React Bootstrap, PostgreSQL
- D&D Character Generator: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Registration & payment app for Seed & Feed: React, Firebase

Senior-Network Support at AT&T Atlanta, GA 2012 – 2018 Scrum Master/Project Manager for Automation Team. Supervised software development projects from end-to-end involving databases, reports, and automation.

- Single point of contact between users and developers assessing business needs
- Processed CodeCloud (Git) pull requests and code merge approvals for developers
- Removed obstacles and helped developers reach contacts and gain access to APIs
- Gathered requirements for hundreds of automation projects
- Led multiple scrum teams concurrently and held daily meetings
- Worked with employees in several locations, including offshore
- iTrack JIRA ticket system and Kanban board SME trained users
- Influenced team to follow Agile Methodology project perspective
- Generated project plans including ROI, scheduling, and time estimates

IT Administrator at EBSCO Research LLC Atlanta, GA 2008 – 2012 IT Administrator for office of 60 employees. Managed computer, printer, and software installs and repairs, as well as, security.

- Networked three new offices cut and ran cables, installed computers, printers and modified desks
- Managed technology relocation to new building & setup of server room
- Ordered and upgraded software, monitors and PCs and communicated with corporate office, VoIP & Internet companies
- Managed System Galaxy, security cameras & DVR, MXIE, upgrades, repairs, purchases, Active Directory

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Snare Drummer – Seed & Feed Marching Abominable Library Manager – Drepung Loseling Monastery Member – OxyGEN – AT&T Organizer – NETREX/TDP – AT&T